splcenter.org 2005-04-03

# SPLCenter.org: Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy sets forth the practices in effect at the Southern Poverty Law Center to protect the privacy of its website visitors and financial supporters, as well as recipients of its print publications. This Policy also outlines how you can update your information or receive additional information. 

**HOW THE CENTER PROTECTS YOUR INFORMATION**  
The Center uses electronic security systems to protect any records containing personal identifying information and limits the number of people who have access to such information. Business partners with whom the Center may share personal information during the course of usual business must abide by confidentiality agreements, which forbid the disclosure of any personal identifying information to additional parties. 

**Online Giving**  
The Center's online donation process occurs in a secure portion of the SPLCenter.org website. Submissions are encrypted and secure from outside users via Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, the industry standard for secure online transactions. All personal information — including credit card number, name, and address — is encrypted so it cannot be read as it travels over the Internet. 

**WEBSITES**  
The Center wants you to have positive experiences at its websites — [SPLCenter.org](http://www.splcenter.org/) and [Tolerance.org](http://www.tolerance.org/) — and to understand your privacy rights while on its websites. If you do not agree with the terms outlined below, do not access the Center's websites. 

**Non-Personal Identifying Information**  
The Center collects and uses non-personal identifying information, including IP addresses and web server log files. It also uses "cookies," small pieces of information used to identify individual computers accessing a website. 

The Center uses this information only in the aggregate. It does not combine non-personal identifying information with personal identifying information, commonly known as "online profiling." At no time is personal information stored in a cookie. 

The Center collects non-personal identifying information from websites in the aggregate. It uses this information to assess aggregate visitor volume and interest, i.e. which site pages are being visited most frequently. 

The Center shares aggregated, non-identifying, demographic information about the websites' usage with its sponsors and partners. For example, the Center might disclose to its donors that 1,000,000 people visited SPLCenter.org in a given year. 

**Personal Identifying Information**  
If you voluntarily provide personal identifying information (such as a first and last name, physical address including a street name, e-mail address, etc.) through online forms, the Center will collect and retain this information. 

The personal identifying information will be used to establish the identity of account holders in order to respond to inquiries or to deliver requested information or services. For example, if you subscribe to one of the Center's e-newsletters, the Center will store your name and e-mail address and send the requested e-newsletters to the e-mail address. 

The Center does not make personal identifying information gathered on its websites available to other organizations, but may share information with business partners, in the usual course of business. For example, the Center may use a third-party vendor to electronically distribute its e-newsletters. In order to send the e-newsletters, the Center must share the e-mail address of subscribers with the vendor. Vendors that provide such services are obligated only to use this information for the purposes for which the Center directs them to use it; namely, providing services directly for the Center. 

Note: If you make an online donation to the Center while at SPLCenter.org or are already a donor, please see the Supporters section of this Privacy Policy for additional information. 

**Protecting Children's Privacy**  
On web pages that are directed toward children under the age of 13 — the "For Kids" section of Tolerance.org, for example — the Center limits its collection of information to non-personal identifying information, such as first name, grade, hometown and state, in an effort to comply voluntarily with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act. 

The Center does not knowingly collect and retain personal identifying information from persons under the age of 13 and has safeguards in place to attempt to ensure it does not inadvertently collect and retain such information. 

The Center strongly urges children to check with their parents before entering information on its websites, and it urges parents to discuss with their children restrictions concerning the online release of personal identifying information to anyone they do not know. 

**Links**  
This policy applies only to the SPLCenter.org and Tolerance.org domains. The Center does not control the privacy policies of other websites to which the Center might link. 

**SUPPORTERS**  
The Southern Poverty Law Center is committed to maintaining the confidence and trust of its financial supporters. 

The Center collects the personal information that supporters provide. After someone donates to the Center, his or her information is added to the Center's membership list. The Center uses this information to keep donors informed about the progress of its programs through print and online mailings and to encourage donors' continued financial support of its work. 

The Center shares donor information with business partners as required in the usual course of business. For example, the Center may use a vendor to assist in the generation and distribution of written communications to donors. 

The Center makes its membership list available to reputable charities and businesses whose information we believe may be of interest to our members. Our ability to share your name with other entities will help build our supporter base. Sharing our list with others is the most cost-efficient way to find new supporters. We hope you agree. The option is yours. If you do not want your name used in this fashion, please let us know. You may contact us via this website by using our contact form. Please include your full name and address with your request. 

**RECIPIENTS OF CENTER PUBLICATIONS**  
As part of its public service, the Center publishes and distributes magazines, handbooks and multimedia kits to help equip teachers, human rights workers, law enforcement and others with tools and resources to promote tolerance in their communities. This portion of the Privacy Policy outlines the Center's privacy practices that relate to people who receive those products. 

In order to receive Center products, an individual must provide personal identifying information (such as a first and last name, physical address including a street name, e-mail address, etc.) The Center will collect and retain this information. 

The Center does not make the personal identifying information of people who order its products available to other organizations. 

The personal identifying information is used to establish the identity of recipients, deliver requested products to recipients and make recipients aware of additional or new Center products that might interest them. In order to evaluate the usefulness of its materials, the Center may also contact, by phone, e-mail or regular mail, persons who have ordered its products. 

The Center may share information with business partners in the usual course of business. For example, the Center may use a vendor to help distribute products. 

The Center does not disclose individual order histories, but may disclose aggregated order histories for its products. For example, the Center would not disclose that "John Doe ordered a copy of this magazine", but could disclose that 300,000 copies of that magazine were ordered. 

**HOW TO UPDATE YOUR INFORMATION**  
Are you a **financial supporter** of the Center and want to update our records? You may do so online.

Are you a subscriber to the **Intelligence Report** and want to update your mailing address? You may do so online.

Are you a subscriber to one of **the Center's e-newsletters** and want to discontinue delivery? You may do so online:

  * [Tolerance.org e-newsletter](http://www.tolerance.org/newsletter/cancellationform.html) (general audience news) 
  * [Teaching Tolerance e-newsletter](http://www.tolerance.org/teach/newsletter/cancellationform.jsp) (news and resources for teachers) 
  * [Mix It Up e-newsletter](http://www.tolerance.org/teens/unnewsletter.jsp) (news for teens) 
  * Hatewatch e-newsletter (news about domestic extremism): [e-mail us](mailto:unsub_hatewatch@newsletter.splcenter.org) with "UNSUBSCRIBE" in the subject line. 
  * Center e-newsletter (news about the Center): [e-mail us](mailto:unsub_center@newsletter.splcenter.org) with "UNSUBSCRIBE" in the subject line. 

For more information, contact: 

> Privacy Coordinator  
>  Southern Poverty Law Center  
>  400 Washington Avenue  
>  Montgomery, AL 36104 

_In the event that this Privacy Policy changes, the Center will post an updated policy on this page, with a notification link to this page from the home pages of SPLCenter.org and Tolerance.org._
